<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://docs.astronomer.io/astro-software-release-notes.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Astro Software Release Notes</title><link>https://docs.astronomer.io/software/release-notes</link><description>Astronomer is committed to continuous delivery of both features and bug fixes to Astro. To keep your team up to date on what&apos;s new, this document will provide a regular summary of all changes released to Astro Software.</description><language>en-US</language><item><title>0.31.1</title><link>https://docs.astronomer.io/software/release-notes#0311</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Release date: December 23, 2022</p><h3>Additional improvements</h3><ul>
<li>You can now configure <code>extraFlags</code> for the Prometheus startup command in the Prometheus Helm chart.</li>
</ul><h3>Bug fixes</h3><ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where logging sidecars would occasionally fail to terminate.</li>
<li>Fixed the following vulnerabilities:
<ul>
<li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2021-46848">CVE-2021-46848</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2021-44716">CVE-2021-44716</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2022-27191">CVE-2022-27191</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2022-27664">CVE-2022-27664</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2022-41717">CVE-2022-32149</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2022-37454">CVE-2022-37454</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2022-41717">CVE-2022-41717</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2022-42919">CVE-2022-42919</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2022-45061">CVE-2022-45061</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2022-46146">CVE-2022-46146</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>]]></description></item><item><title>0.31.0</title><link>https://docs.astronomer.io/software/release-notes#0310</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Release date: December 7, 2022</p><h3>New root user role</h3><p>Astronomer Software's role-based access control (RBAC) system now supports a single root user for each installation. The root user has a non-configurable username and autogenerated password stored as a Kubernetes secret in your installation.</p><p>See <a href="manage-root-user.md">Manage the root user</a>.</p><h3>Manage Astronomer users through a SCIM integration</h3><p>Astronomer Software now supports managing users through System for Cross-domain Identity Management (SCIM), which allows you to automatically provision and deprovision users based on templates for access and permissions. See <a href="integrate-auth-system.md#manage-users-with-scim">Manage users with SCIM</a>.</p><h3>Invite users only through Teams</h3><p>Using the new root user feature, you can now configure Astronomer Software so that users are managed exclusively through Teams. This helps you better integrate with your identity provider (IdP) by ensuring that all users on your platform are authenticated and managed through the IdP. See <a href="import-idp-groups.md#disable-individual-user-management">Disable individual user management</a>.</p><h3>New default resource limits and requests</h3><p>Astronomer Software 0.31 includes new default resource limits and requests on the following resources:</p><ul>
<li>Alertmanager</li>
<li>Elasticsearch</li>
<li>NATS</li>
<li>PostrgeSQL</li>
<li>STAN</li>
<li>Nginx</li>
<li>Grafana</li>
<li>Blackbox exporter</li>
</ul><p>You might experience OOMKill errors or unexpected behavior after upgrading if you use resources beyond the new default limits. To minimize disruption, view resource usage for these components in <a href="grafana-metrics.md">Grafana</a> prior to upgrade and compare this usage to the default resource limits in the <a href="https://github.com/astronomer/astronomer/blob/master/charts/astronomer/values.yaml">Astronomer Helm chart</a>.</p><p>If your current usage is expected and higher than the default resource limits, update the limits in your <code>config.yaml</code> file before upgrading to Astronomer Software 0.31.</p><h3>Additional improvements</h3><ul>
<li>You can now set a custom security context for <code>es-client</code> by setting <code>elasticsearch.client.securityContext.capabilities.add={}</code> in the ElasticSearch Helm chart.</li>
<li>The <strong>Deployment users</strong> page is now paginated in the Software UI.</li>
<li>You can now set <code>astronomer.registry.logLevel</code> to filter which types of logs appear in your Docker registry.</li>
<li>The default Git-sync interval is now 1 instead of 0.</li>
<li>You can now configure a Deployment to have 0 triggerer components.</li>
<li>You can now set <code>astronomer.houston.config.useAutoCompleteForSensativeFields=false</code> to disable autocomplete on sensitive fields in the Software UI.</li>
<li>You can now set <code>astronomer.houston.config.shouldLogUsername=true</code> to include user email addresses in audit logs for logins through the Houston API.</li>
<li><a href="deploy-git-sync.md">Git sync-based Deployments</a> now have a dedicated git-sync relay pod, service, and network policy.</li>
</ul><h3>Bug fixes</h3><ul>
<li>
<p>The Software UI now stores user tokens with <code>httpOnly</code> and <code>secure</code> flags.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixed an issue where the Software UI would occasionally show an incorrect <strong>Extra AU</strong> number for Deployments.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixed the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://security.snyk.io/vuln/SNYK-JS-LOADERUTILS-3043105">CVE-2022-37601</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2022-43680">CVE-2022-43680</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2022-40674">CVE-2022-40674</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixed an issue where you could not access Astronomer Software's Docker registry if you had access to more than 100 Deployments.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixed an issue where the Software UI did not show the correct last used dates for service accounts.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixed an issue where NATS would send false Deployment alert emails.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixed an issue where the configuration in <code>astronomer.houston.updateRuntimeCheck.url</code> was ignored if not all supported Deployment image versions were present in the destination URL.</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></description></item></channel></rss>